<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Yoga</string>
    <string name="trikonaasana">
    1. Stand straight.\n \n
2. First to stand by keeping distance between two feet as shown in the above image.\n
3. Now turn your right leg at around 90 degrees as shown in fig.\n
4. While inhaling raise the both hands in the upward direction in such a way that they will be parallel to the ground and palms facing downwards.\n
5. Now bend at right side while exhaling and your left hand facing towards the ceiling and right hand touching your right toe as shown in fig.\n
6. Keep your eyes facing towards the ceiling (towards the left palm) and do not bend forward or backward. Pregnant women should take care of her balance.\n You can take support of a wall or your friend to maintain the balance.\n
7. Keep inhaling deeply and while exhaling relax the body more and more.\n
8. Stay for 1-2 minutes in this posture.\n
9. Now inhale and get back to original position.\n
10.Repeat from bending left side then the right side.\n</string>


    <string name="trikonaasana_Benefits">1. Stimulate and improve the function of blood through the entire body.\n
2. Strengthens and stretches the hips, back, arms, thighs and leg.\n
3. Reduces blood pressure, stress and anxiety.\n
4. Cure indigestion.\n
5. Gives flexibility to groins, hamstrings and hips.\n
6. Transactional calm the mind.\n
7. Stimulate the function of kidney.\n
8 Helps to remove fats from the waist and thighs.\n
9. This asana improve the balance and increases concentration.\n </string>

    <string name="katichakrasana">
        o Stand up straight with your feet together
o Keep your spine erect keep the shoulders straight\n
o Keep your legs apart from each other equivalent to the shoulders
o Stretch your hands to the front, palms facing each other\n
o Your hands should be in line with the shoulders\n
o First inhale and then while exhaling twist from the waist to the right and look back over the right\n
o Keep your breath out and stay in this position as long as possible\n
o Inhale and slowly come back to the center\n
o Exhale and twist from the waist to the left and look back over the left\n
o Keep your breath out\n
o Stay in this final posture as long as possible\n
o Come back to the center and relax\n
o In the twisted position if you want to stay for longer then you need slowly keep on breathing\n
o This is the complete cycle of this posture\n
o Practice can be repeated 10 to 20 times or even more than that as per the convenience\n
    </string>

    <string name="katichakrasana_benefits">
        o Helps to remove lethargy\n
o Improves the flexibility of the spine and waist\n
o Strengthens the spine and waist
o Good for relieving constipation\n
o Opens up the neck and shoulders\n
o Provides a stretch in different muscles of arm, abdomen and legs\n
o Helps to relive back pain\n
    </string>

    <string name="hastpadasana">
        1. Stand erect and keep both the legs touching each other.\n\n
2. Take a deep breath and keep both the hands up.\n\n
3. Now go on exhaling. Bend in the front.\n\n
4. Place both the hands on the ground on both the sides of the legs.\n\n
        5. Touch the head on the knees.\n\n
6. Do not bend the knees.\n\n
      7. Hold the breath outside.\n\nStand steadily in this bent position.\n\n
8. How to release the stretch\n\n
9. Maintain position and suspension of breath 6 seconds.\n\n
10. Inhale and then return to the starting position\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="hastapadasana_benefits">
        1. Disorders of the belly and digestive system are corrected\n
        2. The chest and hands become stronger and you become well balanced, beautiful and good looking\n
3. Diseases of the feet and fingers are also corrected\n
    </string>

    <string name="ardhachakrasana">
1. Stand straight with feet together and arms alongside the body\n\n
2. Balance your weight equally on both feet
3. Breathing in, extend your arms overhead, palms facing each other\n\n
4. Breathing out, gently bend backwards pushing the pelvis forward, keeping the arms in line with the ears, elbows and knees straight, head up, and lifting your chest towards the ceiling\n\n
5. Hold\n\n
        7.Breathing in, come back up\n\n
6. Breathing out, bring the arms down and relax\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="ardhachakrasana_benefits">
        1. Stretches the front upper torso.\n
2. Tones the arms and shoulder muscles\n
    </string>
    <string name="vrikshasana">
    1. Stand erect\n 2. Keep the feet together\n
3. Fold the right leg and placed it at the top of left thighs with the toes of right leg should pointed downwards\n
4. The right leg should perpendicular to the left leg\n
5. Extend your arms above your head\n
6. Inhale and try to make Namaskar mudra with your palms\n
7. Balance the pose as long as you can because balancing is utmost important in Tree pose\n
8. Try to make your spine straight and feel the stretching from toes to fingers\n
9. With deep exhale bring your arms and leg down\n
10. Repeat the same with left leg\n It completes one round\n
11. Do three-five rounds\n
12. No\n of rounds may increase as per your convenience\n
</string>

    <string name="vrikshasana_benefits">
        1. This pose leaves you in a state of rejuvenation\n 2. It stretches the legs, back and    arms, and invigorates you\n
3. It brings balance and equilibrium to your mind\n
4. It helps improve concentration\n
5. This posture has been found to relieve some cases of sciatica\n
6. It makes the legs strong, improves balance, and opens the hips\n
7. Helps those who are suffering from sciatica\n
    </string>

    <string name="pashchim_namaskarasana">
1. Start with Tadasana pose(Standing Staight and streching the body upwards\n\n
2. Calm down the shoulders and bend your knees a bit\n\n
3. Convey your arms at the back of your back\n\n
4. As you inhale, turn the fingertips inwards closer to the spine and bring them to face upwards\n\n
5. Ensure that the knees are nonetheless moderately bent\n\n
6. Keep within the function for a few breaths\n\n
7. As you exhale, slowly flip the fingertips downward\n\n\
8. Convey the arms to the facet of the physique and slowly come again into Tadasana\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="pashchimnamaskarasana_benefits">
        1. This Pose Opens the stomach and enable deeper breaths\n
2. Helps to Stretch the shoulder joints and pectoral muscle mass\n
    </string>
    <string name="utkatasana">
        1. Stand erect with your feet slightly apart\n\n
2. Stretch your hands to the front with palms facing downwards\n\n Do not bend your elbows\n\n
3. Bend the knees and gently push your pelvis down as if you are sitting in an imaginary chair\n\n
4. Be comfortable or at least try to be! To get a better feel of the Chair Pose, imagine reading a newspaper or typing on a laptop as you remain seated\n\n
5. Ensure that you keep your hands parallel to the ground\n\n
6. With awareness, sit straight and lengthen your spine\n\n
        7. Relax\n\n
8. Keep breathing and flip through the pages of the newspaper, enjoying national and international news\n\n
  9. Sink deeper into the chair by gradually going down but ensure that your knees don’t go beyond your toes\n\n
10. Keep going down slowly and then sit down in Sukhasana (cross-legged posture)\n\n 11. If you want, you may lie down on your back and relax\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="utkatasana_benefits">
        1. Exercises the spine, hips and chest muscles\n
2. Helps strengthen the lower back and torso\n
3. Tones the thigh, ankle, leg and knee muscles\n
4. Balances the body and brings determination in the mind\n
    </string>


    <string name="janusirsasana">Instruction
1. Sit in Dandasana (Staff Pose) with your legs extended in front of you, toes flexed, quadriceps contracted.\n\n
        2. Place your hands next to your buttocks on the floor and lift the bottom of your belly and the sides of your waist.\n\n
3. Bend your right knee, placing your right foot against your inner left thigh and your right heel close to your perineum, just below your pubic bone. \n\n
        4. Gently swing the right knee away from the left foot so that the thighs form an angle greater than 90 degrees—preferably an angle of 135 degrees.\n\n



5. Fold forward over your left leg from the left hip crease. Reach with your right arm first and hold your left foot from the inside. Contracting your left quadriceps powerfully, use your left hand to grasp the center of the hamstring muscles and—tipping the body to the right—pull0000 toward your left sitting bone to release tension in the tendon that connects your hamstring muscles to your pelvis. \n\n
        6. Then press your left hand into the floor near your left hip and push, lengthening the left waist.\n\n
        7. Keep twisting your body toward the left, working to bring your bellybutton over the center of your left thigh.\n\n    8. Hold your left foot with your left hand from the outside. Move deeper into the fold by holding your right wrist with your left hand.\n\n
    9. Make a fist with your right hand.\n\n
    10. Bending your elbows away from each other, pull your left foot with your arms, lengthening the sides of your waist.\n\n
    11. Rest your forehead on your shin. Breathe deeply for 9 or more breaths. \n\n
    12. Inhaling, lift your head and chest, then release your hands to push the floor away and come out of the pose.\n\n
    13. Change sides. \n\n</string>

    <string name="janusirsasana_benefits">
        1. Energize the body. \n
        2. Improves Digestion. \n
    </string>

    <string name="title_activity_navigation__drawer">Yoga --> Menu</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="about">Yoga’s history has many places of obscurity and uncertainty due to its oral transmission of
        sacred texts and the secretive nature of its teachings\n The early writings on yoga were transcribed on fragile palm
        leaves that were easily damaged, destroyed or lost\n The development of yoga can be traced back to over 5,000 years ago,
        but some researchers think that yoga may be up to 10,000 years old old\n Yoga’s long rich history can be divided into
        four main periods of innovation, practice and development\n
    </string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="urdhvamukha_shvanasana">
1. Lie flat on your belly with the top of your feet facing downwards\n\n
        2. Your arms should be stretched down the length of the body\n\n
3. Bend your elbows and spread your palms beside the lowest rib\n\n
4. As you inhale, press your palms firmly on the mat and slowly lift your torso, hips and knees off the mat\n\n
        5. The entire weight of the body should be resting on the palms and top of the feet\n\n
6. You may look straight ahead or tilt your head slightly backwards\n\n
7. Ensure that your wrists are in line with your shoulders and the neck is not strained\n\n
8. Stay in this pose for a couple of breaths\n\n
9. As you exhale, slowly lower your knees, hips and torso back on the mat\n\n
    </string>
    <string name="urdhvamukha_shvanasana_benefits">1. Stretches and strengthens the back, thus relieving the body of lower back ache\n\n
2. Most of the body weight is borne by the arms and wrists, thus strengthening them\n\n
3. This yoga pose helps improve the body posture and also stimulates the abdominal organs\n\n</string>
    <string name="nadi_shodhan_pranayama">
    1. Sit comfortably with your spine erect and shoulders relaxed\n\n Keep a gentle smile on your face\n\n
2. Place your left hand on the left knee, palms open to the sky or in Chin Mudra (thumb and index finger gently touching at the tips)\n\n
3. Place the tip of the index finger and middle finger of the right hand in between the eyebrows, the ring finger and little finger on the left nostril, and the thumb on the right nostril\n\n 
    4. We will use the ring finger and little finger to open or close the left nostril and thumb for the right nostril\n\n
5. Press your thumb down on the right nostril and breathe out gently through the left nostril\n\n
6. Now breathe in from the left nostril and then press the left nostril gently with the ring finger and little finger\n\n 7. Removing the right thumb from the right nostril, breathe out from the right\n\n
8. Breathe in from the right nostril and exhale from the left\n\n You have now completed one round of Nadi Shodhan pranayama\n\n 9. Continue inhaling and exhaling from alternate nostrils\n\n
10. Complete 9 such rounds by alternately breathing through both the nostrils\n\n 11. After every exhalation, remember to breathe in from the same nostril from which you exhaled\n\n 12. Keep your eyes closed throughout and continue taking long, deep, smooth breaths without any force or effort\n\n
</string>
    <string name="nadi_shodhan_pranayama_benefits">
1. Excellent breathing technique to calm and center the mind\n\n
2. Our mind has a tendency to keep regretting or glorifying the past and getting anxious about the future\n\n 3. Nadi Shodhan pranayama helps to bring the mind back to the present moment\n\n
4. Works therapeutically for most circulatory and respiratory problems\n\n
5. Releases accumulated stress in the mind and body effectively and helps relax\n\n
6. Helps harmonize the left and right hemispheres of the brain, which correlate to the logical and emotional sides of our personality\n\n
7. Helps purify and balance the nadis - the subtle energy channels, thereby ensuring smooth flow of prana (life force) through the body\n\n
8. Maintains body temperature\n\n
</string>


    <string name="urdhva_dhanurasana">
        1. Lie down on your back with feet apart ,bend your knees and place your feet on the ground close to your body\n\n
2. Now bring your palms under your shoulders such that the fingers point towards the shoulders and the elbows are shoulder width apart\n\n
chakrasana step

3. Inhale and press your palms firmly into the floor\n\n
4. Lift your shoulders and elbow firmly into the floor
5. Your Feet should be pressed firmly into the floor\n\n
6. Inhale and lift your hips up\n\n
7. The spine should be rolled up so that it may seem to resemble a semi circular arch or wheel\n\n
8. Straighten out your arms and legs as much as possible so that the hips and chest maybe pushed up\n\n
9. Hold this pose for at least 15-30 seconds\n\n
10. To go back to original, bend your elbows to lower your head and shoulders to the floor\n\n
11. Then bend your knees and bring your spine and hips back to the ground and relax\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="urdhva_dhanurasana_benefits">1. Stretches the chest and lungs \n
2. Strengthens the arms and wrists, legs, buttocks, abdomen, and spine\n
3. Stimulates the thyroid and pituitary\n
4. Increases energy and counteracts depression\n
5. Therapeutic for asthma, back pain, infertility, and osteoporosis\n
    </string>
    <string name="ardha_salabhasanaa">    1. Lie on your stomach with your legs straight and arms stretched forward\n\n
    2. Inhale and raise one leg and the opposite arm at same time\n\n
    3. Keep the shoulder in line with the ear, and the raised leg in the centre of the bodyline\n\n
    4. Hold the position for 10 - 30 seconds\n\n
    5. Exhale and lower the arm and the leg\n\n
    6. Repeat on the other side.\n\n</string>

    <string name="ardha_salabhasana_benefits">1. Strengthens the arms, shoulders, muscles of the back, especially the lower back and abdominal muscles
Stimulates the autonomic nervous system
2. Stimulates appetite and the digestive process, balances the functioning of the liver and other abdominal organs, and alleviates stomach disorders</string>


    <string name="garudasana">
        1. Stand straight on both feet\n\n
        2. Raise the right leg and wrap it around the left leg\n\n
3. The right thigh should be over the left thigh and the right feet will touch the calf muscles from behind\n\n
\t garudasana step1

4. Similarly wrap the right hand around the left hand.\n\n
5. Now place the palms together to resemble the beak of an eagle.\n\n
\t garudasana step2

6.Try to maintain the balance and slowly bend the left leg and lower the body until right toes touch the ground.\n\n
7.Try to remain in this pose for long as you can maintain the balance.\n\n
\t garudasana step3

8.Concentrate on balancing the body pose\n\n
9.Now straighten the left leg and unwrapthe right leg. Also release the right arm and come to normal standing position,\n\n
10.Relax for sometime and repeat the same process.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="tagline">"The Way to Explore Life"</string>

    <string name="garudasana_benefits">1. It enhances the sense of balance of the body\n
2. It also strengthen the muscles of the legs\n
3. It can loosen the joints of the legs\n
4. It alleviates sciatica and rheumatism in the leg joints\n</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>
</resources>
